(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-02T21:29:14.563102",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Regular Outfit 缶バッジ・アクリルスタンド
[Regular Outfit] Can Badge & Acrylic Stand
アソビまわり隊！デビュー記念
[Asobi Mawaritai!] Debut Celebration Merch
騒ぎまくるGIGA TIME!
[High-Energy GIGA TIME!]
収録イラストを一部公開！「あおちひめいあ」は両スタートデッキに収録！
[hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME] Card sleeves & decks! Aochi Himeia is in both Start Decks!
スターティングボイス 9月25日販売開始
[Starting Voice] On sale September 25th
PC用動く壁紙
[Animated Wallpapers for PC]
Regular Outfit 缶バッジ・アクリルスタンド
[Regular Outfit] Can Badge & Acrylic Stand
アソビまわり隊！デビュー記念
[Asobi Mawaritai!] Debut Celebration Merch
騒ぎまくるGIGA TIME!
[High-Energy GIGA TIME!]
収録イラストを一部公開！「あおちひめいあ」は両スタートデッキに収録！
[hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME] Card sleeves & decks! Aochi Himeia is in both Start Decks!
スターティングボイス 9月25日販売開始
[Starting Voice] On sale September 25th
PC用動く壁紙
[Animated Wallpapers for PC]
Regular Outfit 缶バッジ・アクリルスタンド
[Regular Outfit] Can Badge & Acrylic Stand
アソビまわり隊！デビュー記念
[Asobi Mawaritai!] Debut Celebration Merch
騒ぎまくるGIGA TIME!
[High-Energy GIGA TIME!]
収録イラストを一部公開！「あおちひめいあ」は両スタートデッキに収録！
[hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME] Card sleeves & decks! Aochi Himeia is in both Start Decks!
スターティングボイス 9月25日販売開始
[Starting Voice] On sale September 25th
のじゃー！
Noja!
のじゃーーーー！！！
Nojaaaa!!!
うん、めっちゃエコーかかっちゃった。
Wow, that had way too much echo.
めっちゃエコーかかっちゃったのじゃ。
That had way too much echo, noja!
あらら？メラメラ？
Oh my? Mela mela?
あちちメラ！
Achichi mela!
ホロライブあそびまわり隊ご利益担当の、ひきこもり、あおちひめいあ。
I'm Aochi Himeia, the shut-in blessings officer of Hololive's Asobi Mawaritai!
あちちメラメラのじゃー！
Achichi mela mela, noja!
おぬしら今日は、今日も元気？
How are you all doing today? Doing well?
いい一日を過ごせたかの？
Did you have a wonderful day?
今日お仕事とかじゃったかの？お仕事とか学校とかじゃった？
Did you have work today? Work or school?
もしかして、わしの歌枠を、歌配信をすっごい楽しみにしていたんじゃないの？
Or perhaps... you were really looking forward to my singing stream?
わしの歌配信があるからお仕事頑張れたよー、とかの人もいるんじゃないの？
Maybe some of you worked hard today just because of my singing stream?
どうじゃどうじゃ？
How about it? Hm?
今日お休みじゃった？お休みもいいの。
Or were you off today? Days off are nice too.
これからいい一日に、一日になる。そうじゃ。
From here on, it'll be a great day. That's right!
わしがね、おぬしらの一日をもっともっといい一日にしちゃうのじゃ！
I'm going to make your day even more wonderful!
のじゃのじゃ、夜から仕事？
Noja noja, you have a night shift?
じゃ、仕事前にわしの歌を聴いて元気にするのがいいと思うのじゃ。
Then you should listen to my singing before work to energize yourself.
げん、元気を、元気を出すのがいいと思いますのじゃ。
I think getting energized is a great idea, noja.
わしのためにやること早めに終わらせた？やったのじゃー！
You finished your tasks early for me? Yay!
いつもさ、わし配信さ、最近ずっと19時から？19時からなんじゃけど、ちょっと早いよね。
Lately, my streams have been starting at 7:00 PM, which is a bit early.
ちょっと早めの時間に配信いつも始めるんじゃが、
Even though I always start at a slightly early time...
わしのために時間とかね、合わせてくれてありがとう、いつも。
thank you for adjusting your schedule for me, as always.
うん、リアタイするのってやっぱスケジュールとかさ、その都合があるじゃろ？
To catch it live, you have to manage your schedule and plans, right?
じゃから、合わせるの大変だと思うんじゃが、ありがとうなのじゃ。
So I know it must be tough, but thank you so much.
嬉しいのじゃ。宿題やりながら聴いてる？いいこと、勤勉なのはいいことですのじゃ。
I'm so happy. You're doing homework? Good job! Being diligent is a great thing.
作業用BGMにしてほしいのじゃ。ちょうどいい時間？
I'd love for this to be your background music. Is this a perfect time?
やったのじゃーー！！
Yay!!!
「この日のために生きてたかもしれない」
"I might have been living just for today."
そう思ってもらえるように、そう思ってもらえるように頑張りますのじゃ。
I'll do my best to make you feel that way!
あのね、おぬしらが多分わしが歌うとこ聴きたいんじゃないかなって曲もね、今日、
Today, I've prepared some songs that I think you'd love to hear me sing...
ご用意してきたので、一番最後に、一番最後に持ってくのじゃ。
and I've saved them for the very, very end!
「やっぱボカロ歌うか？」ボカロも歌うのじゃ。
"Will you sing Vocaloid?" Yes, I will sing Vocaloid too!
ボカロも歌うけど、あの、なんじゃ、
I'll sing Vocaloid, but...
最初から全曲ボカロなのは、ちょっと、もっといっぱいの人に
singing only Vocaloid from the very beginning...
聴いてまらいたいと思ったから、ボカロ以外の曲もね、用意してきましたのじゃ。
might not appeal to everyone, so I prepared some non-Vocaloid songs too!
うん。
Yes.
もし、今日ね、聴きたかった曲が聴けなかったとしてもね、今後たくさんね、歌配信やっていきたいと思うから、
Even if you don't hear your favorite song today, I plan to do many more singing streams...
また今後に期待して、
so please look forward to the future streams...
いただけると嬉しいです。のじゃ。
and I'd be very happy if you do, noja.
あ！水こぼしちゃった。
Ah! I spilled my water.
のじゃ。ちょ、ティッシュ、ティッシュ。
Noja. T-tissue, tissue...
ティッシュ...ティッシュ...
Tissue... tissue...
ちょっと待つのじゃ。ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっと待つのじゃ。
Wait a moment. Wa- wa- wait a moment.
あのの、あのね、
Um, you see...
あ！ののじゃ、あー
Ah! ...you see, ah...
ちょっちょ、落ち着く、落ち着くのじゃ。落ち着くのじゃ！
Wait, calm down, let's calm down. Calm down!
なんか、あの、紙コップに水を入れてるんじゃが
Well, you see, I put water in a paper cup,
ちょっと触るとね、こぼれちゃうから。要、要注意、要注意ですのじゃ。よし。
and if I touch it just a little, it spills, so... caution, absolute caution is needed. Okay.
まあ、まあこんなんで。こんなんでいいじゃろ。
Well, well, like this. This should be fine.
うん。よいしょ。落ち着くのじゃ。
Yes. Heave-ho. Let's calm down.
やっぱあの... あ、わしが歌うとこ...
After all... Ah, where I sing...
あ、ていうか、デビュー1周...年？
Ah, wait, 1... year debut anniversary?
いっしゅ、1周年、1周年じゃない。もうダメだ、気が早い、気が早い！もうダメじゃ、もう...
One we-... 1 year, it's not 1 year! Oh no, I'm getting ahead of myself, getting ahead of myself! Oh no, I'm already...
焦、焦りまくってるのじゃ。大焦りですのじゃ。
freaking, freaking out. I'm in a huge panic.
デビュー1週間！1週間！1週間が経ちましたのじゃ！
It's been 1 week since my debut! 1 week! 1 week has passed!
1週間...まだそんな1週間も経ってないイメージなんじゃが、意外と時が経つのは早いもの。
1 week... It feels like it hasn't even been a week yet, but time flies by surprisingly fast.
うん。1周年じゃないのじゃ。ちょっと間違えたのじゃ。
Yes. It's not the 1st anniversary. I made a little mistake.
1周年はちょっとあの、みっ、ミスったのじゃ。ちょっと...
1st anniversary was a bit of a... a mistake. Just a little...
似てるじゃん！似てるのじゃ、1周年と1週間！
They sound similar! 1 year and 1 week sound similar!
うん。ちょっと、1周年だったら早すぎるのじゃ。
Yes. If it were the 1st anniversary, it would be way too fast.
うん。これからも頑張るから、いっぱい応援してほしいですのじゃ！
Yes. I'll keep doing my best, so I hope you'll support me a lot!
さあ、1週間経ったわしの
Now, since it's been a week, do you...
歌を聞きたいのじゃ？
...want to hear my singing?
聞きたいのじゃ？
Do you want to hear it?
お顔の下を見て、お歌を聞きたいかのう、お主ら？
Look below my face, do you want to hear me sing, my friends?
そろそろお歌聞きたくなってきたんじゃないの？
Aren't you starting to feel like hearing me sing about now?
聞きたくなってきたお主らは、
For those of you who want to hear me sing...
高評価ボタンを押してほしいのじゃーー！
I want you to press the like button!
グッドボタンを押してほしいですのじゃ、プリーズ！
Please press the like button, please!
押してほしいのじゃ。
I'd like you to press it.
おねがいしますのじゃ！
Please do!
もう押した？やったのじゃーー！
Did you already press it? Hooray!
うん。おねがいもしたところで、そろそろお歌を
Yes. Now that I've asked nicely, it's about time...
歌う準備をしていくのじゃ！よいしょ。
...I start preparing to sing! Heave-ho.
よいしょ。のじゃーー！
Heave-ho! Noja!
のじゃー！のじゃのじゃのじゃ、のじゃーー！
Noja! Noja noja noja, noja!
うん。サラマンダーは高評価で成長するタイプ。
Yes, Salamanders are the type that grow through likes.
うん、人間の仕組みは分かんないけど、サラマンダーの仕組み的には
Yes, I don't know how humans work, but as for the mechanics of a salamander...
サラマンダーにはね、高評価を与えるといいのじゃ。評価されると嬉しいですのじゃ。
...it's good to give them likes. It makes us happy to be appreciated.
やったのじゃーー！よし。
Hooray! Alright.
お歌をね、歌おうと思って、あの
I've been planning to sing, and, um...
セットリストみたいな、歌う曲一覧を用意してきたんじゃが、
I prepared a setlist, a list of songs I'm going to sing...
あの、最初緊張しちゃうと思うから、緊張しても歌える曲をね、
but since I think I'll be nervous at first, I put songs that I can sing even when nervous...
最初に持ってきたのじゃ。
...at the beginning of the list.
あ、そう！左下をご覧ください！
Ah, that's right! Please look at the bottom left!
えっと、この歌配信は、えっとJOYSOUNDさんのカラオケを使用させていただいているので、
Um, for this singing stream, since I'm using JOYSOUND's karaoke...
歌唱部分の切り抜き、歌ってるとこ、音楽が載ってるところの動画切り抜きは禁止ですのじゃ！
clipping of the singing parts, where I'm singing and the music is playing, is prohibited!
お主ら、お気をつけくださいのじゃ！うん。
Please be careful about that, everyone! Yes.
よし。最初の曲はこちら。
Alright, the first song is this one.
ちょっと、緊張しても歌える曲を持ってきましたのじゃ。
I brought a song that I can sing even if I'm nervous.
今ちょっと緊張してて、緊張してて、
I'm a bit nervous right now, nervous...
息が上がっていて、早速、早速息が上がっていて、
...and my breath is shallow. Already, my heart rate is up...
うん。
Yes.
これ、キテレツですか？キテレツじゃないのじゃ。あ、キテレツの曲なのじゃ。
Is this Kiteretsu? It's not Kiteretsu— wait, yes, it's a song from Kiteretsu.
「すいみん不足」はキテレツの曲なのじゃ。
"Suimin Busoku" is indeed a Kiteretsu song.
うん。
Yes.
お主ら、眠いんじゃないの？
Aren't you guys sleepy?
現代のお主ら、現代のお主らはなかなか
You modern folks, you guys in modern times...
眠たいお主らが多いんじゃないの？
...tend to be quite sleep-deprived, don't you?
わしの朝活配信を見たりして、朝活配信を見たりして、
Watching my morning streams, and watching my morning streams...
夜も、昨日もね、あそびまるとのコラボ配信をして、なかなか眠たいお主らが多いんじゃないの、と思ったので、
and at night, like yesterday's collab stream with Asobimaru, I thought many of you must be quite sleepy...
眠たい、コロ助のやつ、そうそうそう。
...sleepy. The Koro-suke one, yes, exactly.
眠たいお主ら向けに、こんな曲を用意してきましたのじゃ。よいしょ。
...so I prepared this song for you sleepyheads. Heave-ho.
ちょっと1曲目だから音量感とか大きいとか小さいとかあったら、教えてほしいのじゃ。よいしょ。
Since it's the first song, if the volume is too loud or too quiet, please let me know. Heave-ho.
歌います、すいみん不足！
I'll sing "Suimin Busoku"!
うん。
Yes.
緊張しても歌える可愛い曲なのじゃ。
It's a cute song I can sing even when nervous.
キンコンカンコン、キンコンカンコン
Ding-dong-dang-dong, ding-dong-dang-dong
音デカい？
Is the sound too loud?
音量いい感じ？
Is the volume just right?
じゃ、一旦これでいくのじゃ。
Then I'll go with this for now.
キテレツの曲なのじゃ！
It's a song from Kiteretsu, noja!
今日もいつもの
Today too, the usual...
今日...
Today...
今日もいつものすいみん不足 頭が痛くなっちゃうよ
Today, like always, my lack of sleep makes my head hurt...
いつもの学校のいつもの教室 あの子は今日も元気だね
At the usual school, in the usual classroom, that kid is full of energy again today.
すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep deprivation!
今日もいつものすいみん不足 体がほてってきちゃったよ
Today, like always, my lack of sleep is making my body feel hot.
たくさんやることはあるのに 頭がちっとも働かない
Even though there's so much to do, my brain isn't working at all.
あの子がわたしを悩ませる
That kid is making me worry,
わたしがあの子を悩ませる
and I'm making that kid worry.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is worrying everyone else,
みんなは心を痛めてる
and everyone's heart is aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに暖かいのに
even though the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに
even though the sun is so bright,
どうしてこんなに眠いの
why am I so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep deprivation!
今日もいつものすいみん不足 頭が痛くなっちゃうよ
Today, like always, my lack of sleep makes my head hurt...
いつもの学校のいつもの教室 あの子は今日も元気だね
At the usual school, in the usual classroom, that kid is full of energy again today.
あの子がわたしを悩ませる
That kid is making me worry,
わたしがあの子を悩ませる
and I'm making that kid worry.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is worrying everyone else,
みんなが心を痛めてる
and everyone's heart is aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに暖かいのに
even though the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに
even though the sun is so bright,
どうしてこんなに眠いの
why am I so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん不足
Sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep deprivation!
あの子がわたしを悩ませる
That kid is making me worry,
わたしがあの子を悩ませる
and I'm making that kid worry.
みんながみんなを悩ませる
Everyone is worrying everyone else,
みんなが心を痛めてる
and everyone's heart is aching.
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに暖かいのに
even though the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに
even though the sun is so bright,
どうしてこんなに眠いの
why am I so sleepy?
ああ 空はこんなに青いのに
Ah, even though the sky is so blue,
風はこんなに暖かいのに
even though the wind is so warm,
太陽はとっても明るいのに
even though the sun is so bright,
どうしてこんなに眠いの
why am I so sleepy?
すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん すいみん不足、じゃん！
Sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep, sleep deprivation, ta-da!
のじゃ
...noja.
はぁー、緊張した！
Phew, I was so nervous!
緊張したのじゃ
I was so nervous, noja!
こんなにたくさんの人の前で...
In front of so many people...
歌って、めちゃくちゃ緊張したのじゃ
I sang and got incredibly nervous, noja.
ちょっと、あの、息が上がって心拍数が上がってるから
My breath is a bit short and my heart rate is up...
ちょっと落ち着いていいのじゃ？
So can I calm down for a second, noja?
Can I calm down for a bit, noja?
ちょっとお水飲んでいいのじゃ？
Can I drink some water, noja?
緊張したのじゃー
I was so nervous, noja!
ふぅー
Phew...
切り取りダメだけど、切り取りたいぐらい可愛いじゃあ
They say "No clipping allowed, but she's so cute I want to clip her anyway"...
スクショはオッケーじゃから、スクショして
Screenshots are okay, so take some screenshots...
配信のURLをツイートするのじゃ
and tweet the stream URL, noja.
「メラちゃんの歌可愛すぎワロタ」って呟くのじゃ
And tweet, "Mela-chan's singing is way too cute, lol", noja!
それはオッケーなのじゃ
That is totally fine to do, noja.
はぁ、ちょっとお水飲むのじゃ。緊張した！
Phew, I'm going to drink some water, noja. I was so nervous!
うん、スクショはオッケーなのじゃ
Yes, screenshots are okay, noja!
はぁ、いっぱいの人が見てくれてるのじゃ
Phew, so many people are watching, noja.
ひぃー
Eek!
ドキドキするのじゃ
My heart is pounding, noja.
なんで紙コップか？コップ洗うの面倒くさいからなのじゃ
Why a paper cup? Because washing cups is a pain, noja!
うん、コップ洗うの面倒くさいのじゃ
Yeah, washing cups is a pain, noja.
可愛かった？
Was it cute?
可愛かったのじゃ？
Was it cute, noja?
やったのじゃ。なんか、あの、コメントでめっちゃ「お遊戯会」って
Hooray, noja! Wait, someone in the comments is calling it a 'school recital'...
お遊戯会みたいって
They say it looks like a school recital...
コメントで、コメントでめちゃくちゃお遊戯会って言われてたのじゃ
In the comments, they're saying it's totally like a school recital, noja!
お遊戯会じゃないのじゃ！
It is not a school recital, noja!
いや、最初はね、緊張しちゃうからね
Well, at first, you see, you get really nervous...
緊張しちゃうからな
Because I get nervous,
あの、あんまりね
well, you see...
あの リズムとかメロディとかが
I decided to sing a song whose rhythm
細かくない曲を歌おうと思って
and melody aren't too detailed.
お遊戯会って言われちゃったのじゃ
Someone called it a kindergarten play!
ほっこりした？
Did it warm your heart?
なら良かったのじゃ
Then I'm glad.
ならいいのじゃ。うむ。
That's good then. Yep.
お主ら 父と母になっちゃうの？
Are you guys becoming my father and mother?
わし400歳じゃよ
I am 400 years old, you know?
I am 400 years old!
お主らより年上じゃよ
I'm older than you guys!
おおよそのお主らより
Older than pretty much...
年上
...all of you.
うん、年上なのじゃ
Yep, I'm older.
緊張したけど
I was nervous, but...
頑張って 頑張って歌っていくのじゃ
I'll do my best, my very best to sing.
息が浅い、息が浅い
My breathing is shallow, so shallow.
深呼吸するのじゃ
I'm going to take a deep breath.
お主らもしていいよ
You guys can do it too.
お主らもわしと一緒に深呼吸していいよ
You can take a deep breath with me.
しよう。行くのじゃ。
Let's do it. Here we go.
あ、ちょっとは
Ah, a little bit...
ちょっとはマシになったかの
I think it got a bit better.
I think I feel a bit better.
大緊張でしたのじゃ
I was super nervous!
よいしょ
Heigh-ho.
次の曲
The next song...
次はこちらの曲を歌いますのじゃ
Next, I will sing this song.
ツイートした？
Did you tweet about it?
ツイートありがとうなのじゃ！
Thank you for tweeting!
次はこちらの曲を歌いますのじゃ
Next, I'll sing this song.
ボカロ、ボカロが
Since I really love...
やっぱわし好きじゃから
...Vocaloid after all.
DECO*27さんの
I think I'll sing...
モニタリングを
"Monitoring"
歌おうと思いますのじゃ
by DECO*27.
時代が急に飛んだのじゃ、確かに
We suddenly jumped through eras, indeed!
確かに、確かに
Indeed, indeed!
できるだけいろんな人に分かる曲を
I wanted to include songs that as many people as possible would know,
ちょっとずつ入れようと思って、初めての歌枠だし
bit by bit, since this is my first singing stream.
初めての歌枠だし。うん。
Since it's my first singing stream. Yeah.
そう
That's right.
ベストフレンドじゃない方なのじゃ
It's the one that isn't "Best Friend".
うん
Yeah.
こんばんはなのじゃ
Good evening!
うむ
Yeah.
歌おうと思いますのじゃ
I'm going to sing it.
よいしょ
Heigh-ho.
準備するのじゃ
I'll get ready.
よいしょ
Heigh-ho.
えーっと
Let's see...
できたかの
Is it ready?
よいしょ
Heigh-ho.
モニタリングを
I will sing...
歌うのじゃ
"Monitoring".
ふう
Phew.
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You are all alone,
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know it, I know it.
ビクンビクン震えてさ
Twitching and trembling,
声もダダ漏れなんだわ
even your voice is completely leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just tell the truth.
バレてるんだし 言っちゃえよ
It's already been exposed, so just say it.
効いてんの？
Is it working on you?
普通普通恥ずかしい？
Is it normally, normally embarrassing?
みんな隠しているだけ
Everyone is just hiding it.
よいしょ
Here we go!
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You are alone,
涙してんの 知ってるよ
I know that you are crying.
グスングスンへこんでさ
Sniffling, feeling depressed,
弱音吐いたら in the night
spitting out complaints in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース
We're in this together until morning comes.
何度泣いたって
No matter how many times you cry,
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you every single time.
もう我慢しないで
Don't hold back anymore.
いっぱい出してね
Let it all out.
MWAH! お願い
MWAH! Please,
君が欲しいの
I want you.
慰めさして shake shake
Let me comfort you, shake, shake.
愛の才能で
With the talent of love,
泣いてくれなきゃ
if you don't cry for me,
溢れてしまう 濡れていたい
it will overflow. I want to be wet.
ねえいいでしょ？
Hey, is it okay?
舐めとって 飲み干したいんだったってば
I told you I want to lick it up and drink it dry!
MWAH! お願い
MWAH! Please,
君が欲しいの
I want you.
頼り散らして sit up
Lean on me completely, sit up.
なんて最高ね
How wonderful.
分けてくれなきゃ
If you don't share it with me,
君の痛い 感じてたい
I want to feel your pain.
ねえいいでしょ？
Hey, is it okay?
吸いとって 救いたいんだったってば
I told you I want to suck it out and save you!
見たい 見たい 見たい
I want to see, want to see, want to see
見たい 見たい 見たいの
want to see, want to see, want to see...
君の中
...inside of you.
見たい 見たい 見たい
I want to see, want to see, want to see
want to see, want to see, want to see!
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You are alone,
悔しがってんの 知ってるよ
frustrated. I know it.
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん
My heart goes badum-badum, it's exciting!
君を推すことをやめない
I'll never stop supporting you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君はできる子
Hey, I know. You're a capable person,
知ってるよ
I know it.
つらい時は 弱い位でちょうどいい
When times are tough, being a little weak is just right.
あたしそれでも好きだよ
I still love you regardless.
MWAH! お願い
MWAH! Please,
君が欲しいの
I want you.
名前を呼んでよ
Call my name.
いつだって会いに参上
I'll always show up to see you.
君はひとりだ だから歌う
You are alone, so I sing...
「ひとりじゃない」
..."You are not alone."
ねえいいでしょ？
Hey, is it okay?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだったってば
I told you your solo play is over!
君が病めるときも
Even when you are sick,
あたし側にいるわ
I will be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'll always be watching over you.
そうよ怖くないのよ
That's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
MWAH！お願い
MWAH! Please...
きみが欲しいの
...I want you.
慰めさしてシェイクシェイク
Let me comfort you, shake shake,
愛の talents で
with my talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me,
枯れてしまう 濡れていたい規定
I'll wither away, I want to be wet.
ねえいいでしょう？毟り取って
Hey, it's okay, right? Pluck them out,
飲み干したいんだってば
I said I want to drink it all up!
MWAH！お願い きみが欲しいの
MWAH! Please, I want you.
斬り散らしてシックラブ
Slash and scatter, sick love,
なんて最高ね
isn't it the best?
分けてくれなきゃ
If you don't share it with me,
君の痛い 感じてたい
I want to feel your pain.
ねえいいでしょう？吸い取って
Hey, it's okay, right? Suck it up,
救いたいんだってば
I said I want to save you!
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know... I know you are all alone...
涙してるの知ってるよ 知ってるよ
...shedding tears. I know, I know.
グスングスン 凹んでさ
*Sniffle, sniffle*, feeling down,
弱音に人柄 in the night
letting your weakness show "in the night".
朝が来るまで一緒 護身す
I'll protect you, together until morning comes.
また泣いたって 何度だって
Even if you cry again, no matter how many times,
受け止めてあげる_
I will hold you.
もう我慢しないで 出してってば さあ
Don't hold back anymore, just let it out, come on!
のじゃー！
Noja!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ
Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho...
モニタリングでしたのじゃー！
That was "Monitoring", noja!
ちょっとまだ緊張して
I'm still a bit nervous...
ちょっとまだ、まだまだ、緊張してましたのじゃ
I was still, still quite nervous, noja.
ありがとうなのじゃ_
Thank you, noja.
お遊戯会から10年進んでた？
Did I progress 10 years from the kindergarten recital?
戦いの中で成長してるのじゃ！_
Am I growing in the middle of battle, noja?
うー、恥ずかしいのじゃ
Ooh, I'm embarrassed, noja.
お水飲んじゃお
I'm gonna drink some water.
のじゃ、のじゃ
Noja, noja...
いっぱいの人が見てくれてて嬉しいのじゃ
I'm so happy so many people are watching, noja.
わしの歌好きな人高評価をしてほしいのじゃ
If you like my singing, please leave a like, noja.
なぜならサラマンダーは高評価で育つのじゃ_
Because Salamanders grow from high ratings!
いっぱい褒めてくれる
You all praised me so much...
初配信の、あのわたわたの歌ってみたをチラ見せしたときも_
Even when I showed a sneak peek of my hectic cover during my debut stream.
お主らコメントでめちゃくちゃ褒めてくれてて
You all praised me so much in the comments.
可愛いと上手いしか言われてなくて__
You only said I was cute and good at singing.
すごいね、嬉しいのじゃ_
It's amazing, I'm so happy, noja.
めっちゃ褒めてもらえる、嬉しいのじゃ
I get praised so much, I'm so happy, noja.
何でそんな可愛いか？
Why am I so cute?
お主らが可愛いって言ってくれるからなのじゃ_
It's because you all tell me I'm cute, noja.
褒められたら褒められた分だけ育ちますのじゃ
The more I'm praised, the more I grow, noja.
やったのじゃ、たくさんの褒め
Yay, noja! So much praise.
ちょっとずつ緊張が減ってきているのを感じるのじゃ
I can feel my nervousness slowly fading away, noja.
わしボカロ大好きじゃから、今後もいっぱい歌枠で歌いたい_
Since I love Vocaloid, I want to sing lots in future streams,
ボカロの話もいっぱいしたいなって思うのじゃ
and talk a lot about Vocaloid too, noja.
うむ、のじゃのじゃ
Mmhmm, noja noja.
いずれボカロ縛りもしたいのじゃ
Someday I want to do an all-Vocaloid stream too, noja.
今日はですが、色んな曲を歌いたいと思ったので
But today, I wanted to sing all kinds of songs...
よいしょ_
Up we go!
わしはのアニソンも好きなのじゃ。アニソンも大好きなのじゃ。_
I also like anime songs, noja. I love anime songs too, noja.
アニソン、ボカロも好きじゃけど、作家さんの作る曲も好きで
I like Vocaloid, but I also really like songs made by specific composers.
わしの、ZAQさんの曲すごい好きなんじゃが_
For me, I really love ZAQ's songs.
中二病でも恋がしたいの曲なんじゃが
It's a song from "Love, Chunibyo & Other Delusions".
Sparkling Daydreamっていう曲なのじゃ
It's called "Sparkling Daydream", noja.
すごい好きで
I love it so much.
中二病でも恋がしたいの作品はだいたいの曲がZAQさんが手掛けてて
For "Love, Chunibyo & Other Delusions", almost all the songs are made by ZAQ.
特にわしが一番お気に入りなのは「Across the line」なんじゃが
Especially, my absolute favorite is "Across the line".
今日はね、1期のオープニングの「Sparkling Daydream」を_
Today, I'll be singing "Sparkling Daydream", the opening for season 1.
そうハウリングの人！あの美魚先輩のハウリングを作ってる_
Yes, the Howling person! The one who made Mio-senpai's Howling.
「しじまに響いてよ、My Howling」を作ってる方なのじゃ_
The one who made "Echo in the silence, My Howling", noja.
すごい好きだから、歌っていこうと思いますのじゃ
Since I love it so much, I'm going to sing it, noja.
そう、ぐるぐる回すやつ！サビでぐるぐる回すやつなのじゃ！
Yes, the finger-spinning one! The one where you spin your finger in the chorus, noja!
お主らサビでさ、ぐるぐるのコメントして
Everyone, please comment with "spinning" during the chorus!
おっ？
Oh?
お主 サビで ぐるぐるのコメントしてほしいのじゃ。うんむ。
I want you guys to comment "guru guru" during the chorus. Yes.
よし
Alright.
じゃあ 歌っていこうと
Now, let's sing...
思いおすのじゃ！
...is what I'm thinking!
そ、そのぐるぐるじゃないのじゃ。まあいいや、伝わればいいのじゃ。
N-No, not *that* "guru guru". Oh well, as long as you get it.
伝わればいいのじゃ。
As long as you get it.
よいしょ、よいしょ。歌っていきますのじゃ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho. I'm going to sing!
Sparkling Daydream!
Let's look for
sparkling daydream...
しばらく見つめ合ってから
After staring at each other for a while,
そらすまでに なにを考えてたの？
what were you thinking before looking away?
…気になる
...I'm curious.
唇 尖らせた私を見て
Looking at me pouting,
「どうしたの？」って聞いてくるの
you ask, "What's wrong?"
待ってみるの
I try waiting for that.
誤魔化したあとの独り言は
The whisper after I brush it off
恥ずかしいから
is too embarrassing,
聞かないでくれる？
so could you please not listen?
後に引けないほど 惹かれ合う恋
A love where we're drawn so close we can't pull back,
もう始まってた
had already begun.
夢ならたくさんみた
I've had so many dreams,
冷めたままでもまだ会いたい
but even when wide awake, I still want to see you.
君がそうさせた
You made me this way.
恋は欲張りだね
Love makes us greedy, doesn't it?
飛び跳ねそうな心の
With a heart that's about to leap out,
ゆくままにいこうよ
let's go wherever it takes us.
理想も妄想も現実も
Ideals, delusions, and reality—
全て君を軸に回る
they all revolve around you,
新しい世界へ
to a brand new world.
Looking so crazy...
偶然聞こえた誰かの声が
The voice of someone I happened to hear,
もう一度聞こえたとき
when I heard it once more,
必然を信じた
I believed in destiny.
そんなとき 言葉に意味はなくて
At times like that, words have no meaning,
体が動く 君を探して
and my body just moves, searching for you.
痛み ねじ伏せるように 現実逃避
Escaping reality as if twisting away the pain,
でもそこにも君が現れて
but even there, you appear,
臆病な私すら
and even a coward like me,
抱きしめてくれた
you embraced.
虹がかかる朝
On a morning with a rainbow...
いくのじゃ！
Let's go!
綺麗な空見上げて
Looking up at the beautiful sky,
君と駆ける夢見るの
I dream of running with you.
明日もそうだよ
Tomorrow will be the same, too.
恋は終わらない
This love will never end.
同じ星に生まれた
Born on the same planet,
こんなチャンス他にない
there's no other chance like this.
運命と宿命が巡る
Fate and destiny intertwine,
魔法にかけられるような
as if placed under a spell,
輝く奇跡へ
to a shining miracle.
スパークリングデイドリーム大好きなのじゃ。
I love Sparkling Daydream.
かっこいいし。
It's so cool.
じゃんじゃんじゃんじゃん。
Jan-jan-jan-jan.
理想と妄想と現実は
Ideals, delusions, and reality—
違うようで同じんだ
they seem different but are the same.
形には出来ないけれど
Though I can't put them into words,
どれも大切と悟るの
I realize they're all important,
瞳が夜を忘れない
and my eyes won't forget the night.
夢ならたくさんみた
I've had so many dreams,
冷めたままでもまだ会いたい
but even when wide awake, I still want to see you.
君がそうさせた
You made me this way.
恋は欲張りだね
Love makes us greedy, doesn't it?
飛び跳ねそうな心の
With a heart that's about to leap out,
ゆくままにいこうよ
let's go wherever it takes us.
作曲家さん、作家さんでもあるんじゃけど
She's a composer, a songwriter...
そう、ZAQさんの曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで
Yes, I absolutely love ZAQ's songs.
提供曲ほぼ全部追ってるぐらいね、めちゃくちゃ好きなんじゃが
I follow almost all of her provided songs, that's how much I love them.
そう、じゃからね、あれかも
Yes, that's why...
めちゃ、めちゃ聞き込んでいる
I listen to them over and over.
めっちゃ聞き込んでいるのじゃ
I really listen to them a lot.
すごい、すごい好きなのじゃ
I really, really love them.
大好きな作家さんですのじゃ
She's a songwriter I love so much.
提供もめちゃくちゃ良い
The songs she provides are also great.
中二病でも恋がしたいのあの曲の
Like the song from "Love, Chunibyo & Other Delusions!"
「Across the line」って曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで
I really love the song "Across the line"...
いつか歌枠で歌いたいのじゃ
...and I want to sing it on a singing stream someday.
めちゃ好きなのじゃ
I love it so much.
そうそう、「Classroom」とかそういう「よう実」の曲とかね
Yes, yes, "Classroom" or those "Classroom of the Elite" songs.
「ソララネラ」とかね、そう
Or "Soraranera".
そうそうそうそう、なのじゃ、なのじゃ
Yes, yes, yes, that's how it is.
え、なんか歌めっちゃ褒めてもらえるけど
You guys are praising my singing so much,
歌そんなに自信なかったっくて
but I actually didn't have much confidence.
このライブ入る前にめちゃくちゃ練習して
So I practiced like crazy before this stream.
めちゃくちゃ練習したから
Because I practiced so much,
すごい嬉しいのじゃ
I'm really happy.
お主らが今あげてくれてる曲だいたい全部知ってるのじゃ
I know almost all of the songs you guys are listing right now.
そう、ユーフォニアムも「トゥッティ！」じゃろ
Yeah, like "Tutti!" from Euphonium.
いつか歌いたいのじゃ
I'd love to sing them someday.
めっちゃ褒められる！すごい練習したのじゃ
You're praising me so much! I practiced so hard.
嬉しいですのじゃ、ありがとなのじゃ
I'm so happy. Thank you!
緊張が解けてきたー！緊張解けてきた
My nervousness is finally fading~!
よう実おもろいよね
"Classroom of the Elite" is interesting, isn't it?
お水入れてきていい？
Can I go get some water?
よいしょ
Up we go.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ
Up we go, up we go...
ウォーターサーバーをね、横に置いてるの
I have a water server right next to me.
配信中にね、いつでもね、お水をとれるようにね
So that I can get water anytime during the stream.
ウォーターサーバーをね、横にある
I have a water server right here beside me.
置いているのじゃ、のじゃ
Yes, I keep it here.
次何歌おうとしたんだっけ？ちょっとセトリ見ちゃお
What was I going to sing next? Let me sneak a peek at the setlist.
ちら、ちらちらちら
Peeking...
フォニイ！
Phony!
そうじゃった、そうじゃった
Ah, that's right, that's right.
やはりね、好きなボカロPさんはツミキさんって言ってるので
As I always say, my favorite Vocaloid producer is Tsumiki,
ツミキさんの曲をご用意してきましたのじゃ
so I've prepared a song by Tsumiki.
いつか作家、Classroomの曲も歌いたいのじゃ
Someday, I want to sing "Classroom" songs too.
フォニイ、そう
Phony, indeed.
え、お面つけて歌っちゃおうかな、フォニイだし
Maybe I should wear my mask to sing it, since it's Phony.
お面つけて歌っちゃおうかな
Maybe I should put the mask on.
フォニイ、お面の曲じゃし、MVがね
Phony is a mask-themed song, in the music video at least.
ボカコレ好きなのじゃ！前回のボカコレも見てたのじゃ
I love VocaColle! I watched the previous VocaColle too.
ボカロ好きなのじゃ
I love Vocaloid.
お面つけて歌っちゃおう
Let's sing with the mask on.
雰囲気出るのじゃ、かっこいいお面
It sets the mood. A cool mask.
かっこいいお面なのじゃ
It's a really cool mask.
よし！
All right!
いや、難しいんじゃよな
Man, it's so difficult.
わしね、ボカロ大好きなのじゃが
I love Vocaloid so much,
ボカロってね、いかんせん、早いし、高いし、むずいから
but Vocaloid songs are ultimately fast, high-pitched, and hard.
ちょっと上手に歌えるかがちょっと不安なんじゃが
So I'm a bit anxious if I can sing it well.
不安なんじゃが
I'm quite anxious.
不安なんじゃが、頑張るのじゃ！
I'm nervous, but I'll do my best!
緊張も解けてきたことだし
Now that my tension is easing.
フォニイ歌うのじゃー！
I'm going to sing Phony~!
行くのじゃ
Here I go.
この世で造花より綺麗な花は無いわ
In this world, there are no flowers more beautiful than artificial ones.
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている保存
Because everything is made of lies.
アンティパシーワールド
Antipathy world.
エコー忘れてたのじゃ
I forgot the echo!
絶望の雨は あたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair beats against my umbrella,
湿らす前髪と君の裏面
wetting my bangs and your hidden side.
患わしいわ
It's so annoying.
いつしか言の葉は 互いに枯れきって
Before we knew it, our words completely withered away,
事の実があたしに触れている
and the reality of things is touching me.
パッパッパラッパパパラッパ
Pa-pa-para-pa, pa-para-pa...
パッパラパッパラパッパラパパ 謎謎かぞえて遊びましょう
Pappara, pappara, pappara, papa! Let's count riddles and play!
タタッタラタタッタラタタッタラタッタ 何故何故此処で踊っているでしょう
Tatattara, tatattara, tatattara, tatta! Why, oh why, are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things. What am I, again?
それすら夜の手のひらに解されて 愛のように
Even that is unraveled in the palm of the night... like love.
さようならも言えぬまま泣いたフォニィ
Phony, crying without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニィ
Entangled in lies, I am a phony.
antipathy world
のじゃ〜
Noja~
パッパ！
Pappa!
嫌に成り合って色の目があなたを宥めている
Growing weary of each other, colored eyes are soothing you.
鏡に映るあたしを欠いて 誰しもが目見違ったフェイク
Lacking the me reflected in the mirror, a fake everyone mistook.
妬んで 愛なんてものに群がり それを欲して生きるのだ
Envying, crowding around this thing called love, living on to desire it.
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が通り去っていく 踊り明かせよ
Swimming again today, the night train passes by. Dance the night away!
パッパ！
Pappa!
パッパラパッパラパッパラパパ 謎謎騙して歌いましょう
Pappara, pappara, pappara, papa! Let's deceive riddles and sing!
タタッタラタタッタラタタッタラタッタ 何故何故此処が痛むのでしょう
Tatattara, tatattara, tatattara, tatta! Why, oh why, does it hurt here?
散々日々は変わらないわ
These miserable days won't change.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
This rain of despair won't stop.
さようならも言えぬまま泣いたフォニィ
Phony, crying without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まっているただ
Entangled in lies, simply...
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things. What am I, again?
それすら夜の手のひらに解されて 愛のように
Even that is unraveled in the palm of the night... like love.
さようなら またねと呟いたフォニィ
"Goodbye, see you again," whispered Phony.
嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニィ
Entangled in lies, I am a phony.
造花だけが知っている 秘密のフォニィ
Only the artificial flowers know the phony secret.
のじゃ〜〜〜！
Noja~~~!
フォニィでしたのじゃ。
That was Phony, noja.
のじゃ〜！
Noja~!
かっこよかったのじゃ？お面つけたのじゃ。いい感じ？かわ、かっこいい？
Was it cool, noja? I put on a mask, noja. Does it look good? Cu- cool?
やったのじゃ〜！
Yay, noja~!
え、大褒め？ベタ褒め？
Eh, lots of praise? Excessive praise?
あははは！ベタベタ褒め褒めじゃない？ベタベタ褒め褒めなのじゃ。
Ahahaha! Isn't it super-duper praise? It's super-duper praise, noja.
やったのじゃ！
Yay, noja!
え、なんかお歌歌ってこんなに褒められて嬉しいのじゃ。
Eh, I'm so happy to be praised this much for my singing, noja.
のじゃ、いつかわしが、ソロライブできることになったら聴きに来てね。聴きに来てほしいのじゃ。
Noja, if I ever get to do a solo live concert someday, please come listen. I want you to come listen, noja.
とっても嬉しいから。
Because it would make me so happy.
うん、とっても嬉しいからその時は聴きに来てほしいのじゃ。のじゃ。
Yes, it would make me so happy, so please come listen then, noja. Noja.
ありがとうなのじゃ。
Thank you, noja.
やったのじゃ〜！
Yay, noja~!
はぁ〜、嬉しいのじゃ。
Haa~, I'm so happy, noja.
ツミキさんの曲めっちゃ好き。めっちゃ好き。
I really love Tsumiki-san's songs. I really love them.
ボカロも好きだし、提供曲も好きだし、
I love Vocaloid, and I also love their commissioned songs,
ノーメロとかも好きだし。
and I love NOMELON NOLEMON too.
今後色んな曲を歌いたいなーって思うのじゃ。
I think I want to sing all kinds of songs in the future, noja.
うん、色んなの歌いたいのじゃ。
Yes, I want to sing a variety of songs, noja.
いや緊張だいぶ落ち着いてきたのじゃ。最初、最初ガチガチじゃったから。
Man, my nervousness has really calmed down, noja. At first, I was super stiff.
チョウカゲヒメ好きになったのはボカロから？
"Did you start liking Chokagehime through Vocaloid?"
そうじゃの。チョウカゲヒメは、あの、始まる前に、作品が始まる前に歌ってみたの、その早見沙織さんとかの声優さんの、ボカロ曲歌ってみたとかが、上がってたじゃろ？
That's right. For Chokagehime, well, before it started—before the series began—there were Vocaloid song covers uploaded, right? Like voice actors like Hayami Saori-san singing them.
それでチョウカゲヒメを知って、あ、なんかこういうのがあるのかと思って、
That's how I learned about Chokagehime, and I thought, "Oh, so there's something like this."
み、見ようと思って。見たら、
And decided to watch it. When I watched it,
好きになったのじゃ。
I fell in love with it, noja.
うん。のじゃ。のじゃ。そうですのじゃ。
Yes. Noja. Noja. That's how it was, noja.
あ〜、落ち着いてきたのじゃ〜。
Ah~, I've really calmed down, noja~.
始まった時ガチガチガチガチ、ガチガチだったのじゃ。
When it started, I was so stiff, stiff, super stiff, noja.
ホロライブの曲も歌うのかな？え〜、最後までいたらなんか聞けちゃうんじゃないかなのじゃ？
"Will you sing Hololive songs too?" Eh~, if you stay until the end, maybe you'll get to hear some, noja?
最後までいたら、もしかしてホロライブの歌も聞けちゃうかも、聞けちゃうかも！
If you stay until the end, maybe, just maybe, you might get to hear Hololive songs too! You might!
...面白い のじゃ。
...might be interesting, right?
のじゃ？
Right?
最後までいるといいことがある気がするのじゃ。
I feel like if you stay until the end, something good will happen!
うん、声震えてた。
Yeah, my voice was shaking.
睡眠不足歌ってるとき、本当に声めっちゃ震えてたのじゃ。ガチガチ。
When I was singing "Insomnia," my voice was really shaking. I was so stiff!
あの、今きたお主らは、アーカイブで...
For those of you who just arrived, please watch the archive...
アーカイブでわしの、わしのガチガチの睡眠不足聞いてほしい。
I want you to listen to my super-stiff "Insomnia" in the archive.
ガチでもう、めっちゃ緊張した。めっちゃ緊張したのじゃ。
Seriously, I was so nervous. I was incredibly nervous!
うん、めっちゃ緊張してたのじゃ。うん。
Yeah, I was super nervous. Yes.
プルプルだった。プルプルじゃった。うん。
I was trembling. Trembling. Yes.
うん。プルプルじゃった。
Yeah, I was shaking like a leaf.
でも、あの、絶対最初緊張するかなって思って、
But, you know, I knew I would definitely be nervous at first,
絶対最初緊張するかなって思ったから、
since I thought I'd definitely be nervous in the beginning,
あの、最初は緊張しても歌える曲をね、持って来たのじゃ。
I brought a song that I can sing even when I'm nervous for the start.
何時までか？あと何曲かの？
Until what time? How many songs left?
何曲じゃったっけ？
How many songs was it again?
1、2、3...ちょっと忘れちゃった。
1, 2, 3... I forgot a bit.
忘れちゃったけど、忘れちゃったけど、
I forgot, but... I forgot, but...
ちょっと待っての。ちょっと待っての。
Wait a moment. Wait a moment.
あとね、今フォニイまで歌ったでしょ。あと3曲！
And then, I just sang "Phony" right? 3 more songs!
今日はね、あと3曲ね、歌おうと思ってね、来たのじゃ。
Today, I came planning to sing 3 more songs.
うん。あと3曲歌わせていただきますのじゃ。
Yeah. I will let myself sing 3 more songs.
あの、今週の日曜日？
Um, this Sunday?
日曜日も歌枠あるから、日曜日も歌枠あるから、
Since I have another singing stream on Sunday as well...
じゃから、あの、喉をね、いたわりつつ歌おうと思うのじゃ。
So, I'm thinking of singing while taking care of my throat.
アンコールはないのじゃ。うん。
There won't be an encore. Yep.
次の曲はね、次もアニソンなのじゃ。よいしょ。
The next song is... the next one is an anime song too. Heave-ho!
でれん！「アイオウタエ」って曲を、
Ta-da! A song called "Ai o Utae,"
次は歌おうかなって思っておって。
I think I'll sing that next.
この曲アニソンなんじゃが、
This song is an anime song, but...
物語シリーズ、物語シリーズの曲なんじゃが、
It's a song from the Monogatari Series...
あの、作曲がね、作曲がじんさんなんじゃよ。
And the composer is actually Jin!
じんさんってボカロPのさ、そのカゲプロとか作ってらっしゃるさ、いるじゃの？
Jin, the Vocaloid producer who made KagePro and stuff, you know?
そう、じんさんが作曲なんじゃよ。そう。
Yes, Jin is the composer. Indeed.
から、アニソンも好きだし、ボカロも好きだし、ってわしにとって...
So, since I love anime songs and Vocaloid, to me...
すごい好き、すごい好きな曲なのじゃ。うん。
it's a song I love, a song I absolutely love. Yeah.
そうですのじゃ。
That's how it is.
よし、歌っちゃおうかな？
Alright, shall I sing it?
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Up we go, up we go.
のじゃ。のじゃ。のじゃ。
Noja. Noja. Noja.
よいしょ。よいしょ。よいしょ。
Here we go, here we go, here we go.
うんと、こう。こう。
Let's see, like this. Like this.
よし！「アイオウタエ」、物語シリーズの、
Alright! "Ai o Utae," from the Monogatari Series...
じんさんの曲、歌っちゃいますのじゃ。
a song by Jin, I'm going to sing it!
のじゃ！
Here we go!
本当の気持ちを 心臓に合わせて
My true feelings, matching the beat of my heart,
自分らしく さあ話そう
let's speak them in my own way.
あ、エコー！エコー忘れてたのじゃ。
Ah, echo! I forgot the echo effects.
はい！はい！はい！はい！のじゃ！のじゃ！のじゃ！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Noja! Noja! Noja!
平凡な金曜日 落ち込んだ毎日は
On a mundane Friday, during depressing days,
不安と後悔の連続
it's a series of anxiety and regret.
作戦を考えて
Thinking of a strategy,
「この気持ちどうやって言おうかな」って今日も終わる
"How should I convey these feelings?" and today ends again.
君の目が泳いだら
If your eyes wander,
不安でしょうがないんだよ
I can't help but feel incredibly anxious.
「嫉妬しちゃう 嫌だ 嫌だ」ってうつむいて 堪らないんだ
Muttering "I'm jealous, I hate this, I hate this" with head bowed, it's unbearable.
本当はね ずっと君と二人だけが良かったんだ
To tell the truth, I always wanted it to be just the two of us.
『純粋なアイのコトバ』笑わないでよねえ
Don't laugh at my "pure words of love," okay?
きっとまたそんな君を「諦めてやるもんか」って
I'll surely tell myself "I won't give up on you yet" again...
必死に答えを探す 馬鹿みたいだね、あぁ
as I desperately search for an answer. It's so foolish, ah...
余裕なんてないんだよ
I don't have any composure left.
迂闊に話せない
I can't just speak carelessly.
溜め息をついて さあリセットしよう
Sighing deeply... Now, let's reset.
出来合いの言葉で 飾った想いなんて
Feelings decorated with ready-made words...
２％も伝わらない
won't even convey two percent of it.
本当の心を言葉にしよとして...
Trying to put my true heart into words...
言葉にしようとして
Trying to put it into words,
「気取ってないか」って 落ち込む
I feel down, wondering, "Am I being pretentious?"
おどけた態度取ってさ
Even if I act playful,
君は変わらないよね
you remain unchanged.
ホント解らない
I really don't understand...
何で君ばっか
Why do I only care
気にしちゃうんだ
about you?
最初から こんな心
If only I hadn't known
知らなければ 良かったんだ
this kind of feeling from the start.
「繊細なアイのコトバ」
The delicate "words of love"...
なくなってよ あぁ
just disappear. Ah...
きっとまた この気持ちが
Even if this feeling
私を苦しめたって
torments me again,
ホントの想いは消えない
my true feelings won't fade away.
知ってるけど あぁ
I know that, but... ah...
とめどない溜息
With endless sighs,
繰り返しても ほら
even if I repeat them, look,
「まだまだ」って 立ってるでしょ？
I'm still standing, saying "not yet," right?
あの日 あの時に
Because on that day, at that moment,
何かが生まれたから
something was born.
きっとまた 辛い事だってあるのも当然
Naturally, there will be tough times again.
あのね、ホントはね
You know, the truth is...
涙を隠しながら
While hiding my tears,
絶対に諦めないように
vowing never to give up,
息を吸い込む
I take a breath.
「ホントはね、
The truth is,
ずっとずっと言えなくて
I couldn't say it for the longest time,
寂しかったんだ」
and I was so lonely...
心臓がエールを送る
My heart sends me cheers.
このまま
Just like this...
ホントだよ、
It's true,
ずっとずっと二人だけでいたかったんだ
I wanted to be just the two of us forever.
「純粋なアイのコトバ」
The pure "words of love"...
やっと会えたね あぁ
We finally met. Ah...
最初から この気持ちが
From the very beginning, this feeling
君だけに向いてるんだって
has been directed only at you.
真剣な恋の行方
Where will this serious love go?
どうなるんだろうねぇ
I wonder what will happen...
目と目を合わせたら
If our eyes meet,
怖がらずに ほら
look, don't be afraid.
話してみよう
Let's try to talk
自分だけの心を
about my own heart.
のいじゃー！
Noija!
のいじゃ。のいじゃ。
Noija. Noija.
「何でも知ってそうな声」？
"A voice that sounds like it knows everything"?
何でもは知らないのじゃ。
I don't know everything, noja.
知ってることだけしか知らないのじゃ。
I only know what I know, noja.
ネットミームはあんまり詳しくありませんのじゃ。
I'm not very familiar with internet memes, noja.
でも、あの、知ってるミームがあると言いたくなっちゃいますのじゃ。
But when there's a meme I know, I just want to say it, noja.
のいじゃ。
Noija.
アイのウタエでした！
That was "Ai no Utae"!
のいじゃー！
Noija!
うん。
Yeah.
お歌は練習中だけど、いっぱい褒めてもらえて嬉しいですのじゃ。
I'm still practicing singing, but I'm so happy to receive so many compliments, noja.
噛みました？
Did I stutter?
噛みまみたのじゃ！
I shtuttered, noja!
のいじゃー！
Noija!
うむ。
Mhm.
ふぅ。
Phew.
のいじゃ。
Noija.
いっぱい褒められてる。
I'm getting so many compliments.
うふふ。いっぱい褒められてる。
Hehe, I'm getting so many compliments.
のじゃー！
Noja!
やったのじゃ！
I did it, noja!
うん。
Yeah.
のじゃ、のじゃ。
Noja, noja.
「江戸時代に流行った曲も聴きたい」？
"Do you also want to hear songs that were popular in the Edo period"?
うーん、わし現代っ子じゃから。
Hmm, after all, I'm a modern child.
江戸時代もずっと山、
During the Edo period, I was always in the mountains.
火消しのとき以外は、火事があるときは
Except for when I went down to the town as a firefighter
街に下りて手伝ってたけど、
to help when there was a fire...
火事がないときは基本、山におりましたのじゃ。
When there was no fire, I basically stayed in the mountains, noja.
つーちゃんが褒めてくれる。ありがとうなのじゃ。
Tsu-chan is praising me. Thank you, noja.
うん。
Yeah.
のじゃ。
Noja.
カゲロウデイズ歌うの聴きたい？ メカクシティアクターズのじゃ。
Want to hear me sing "Kagerou Days"? From Mekakucity Actors, noja.
いつか歌いたいのじゃ。
I'd like to sing it someday, noja.
うむ。
Mhm.
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ。
Noja, noja, noja.
いっぱいの人間が、見てくれてて嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm so happy that so many humans are watching me, noja.
やったのじゃー！
I did it, noja!
「育ての親から流行りの曲知ったの」？
"Did you learn popular songs from your foster parents"?
ううん、曲はね、インターネットで知ったのじゃ。うん。
No, I learned about songs on the internet. Yeah.
曲はインターネットで知ったのじゃ。
I learned about songs on the internet, noja.
ボカロスが大好きなのじゃ。
I love Vocaloid, noja.
楽器弾けないのじゃ。
I can't play any instruments, noja.
カゲプロもいつか歌いたいのじゃ。
I want to sing KagePro songs someday too, noja.
まあまあお主ら、お主ら。そう、そう急かすでない、急かすでない。
Now, now, everyone. Indeed, don't rush me, don't rush me.
まだ初めてのお歌枠なんじゃから。
After all, this is only my first singing stream.
まだ初めてなんじゃから。うん。
After all, it's my first time. Yeah.
ちょっとずつ、ちょっとずつですの...あ、噛んじゃった。
Step by step, step by step... Ah, I stuttered!
ちょっとずつですのじゃ。
Step by step, noja.
うん、ちょっとずつですのじゃ。
Yeah, step by step, noja.
うん。
Yeah.
日曜日にもお歌枠あるから、
Since I'll also have a singing stream on Sunday...
日曜日にもお歌枠ありますのじゃ。配信終わったらそれ告知するのじゃ。
Yes, I'll have a singing stream on Sunday. I'll announce it after this stream ends, noja.
うん。
Yeah.
まあまあまあ、急かすでない。
Now, now, don't rush me.
いつかね。
Someday.
いつか歌うからね、まだまだですのじゃ。まだ初回ですのじゃ。
I'll sing them someday, but there's plenty of time. This is only my first time, noja.
うん、うん。のじゃ、のじゃ。
Yeah, yeah. Noja, noja.
のじゃ。
Indeed.
はぁ。
*Sigh*
じゃ、次の曲歌っちゃおうと思うんじゃが。よいしょ。
Well, I think I'll sing the next song. Yoisho.
じゃじゃーん！
Tada!
わしが、わしがあのホロライブの...
I... during my Hololive...
わしがホロライブの、あの、オーディションの時に、
...when I was in the Hololive audition,
送った曲。
...this is the song I submitted.
うん。
Yeah.
わしがホロライブのオーディションで、
During my Hololive audition,
あの、「この曲が好きなんです」って話をね、
I talked about "I really love this song"
ながながと語った、
at great length...
熱く語った曲。
...it's the song I passionately talked about.
すごい好きな曲なんじゃが、すごい好きなんじゃけど、
I love this song so much, but...
わしが好きなのって、カフさんが歌うトウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴじゃから、
...since the one I love is Kafu-san's version of Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous,
そう、ボーカルが、カフの、カフさんの
yeah, the vocals, Kafu-san's...
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴがすごい好きじゃから、
...I love Kafu-san's Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous so much.
自分で歌うといまいち物足りねえのじゃ。正直。
So honestly, when I sing it myself, it feels a bit lacking.
正直。
Honestly.
正直物足りない。正直物足りないけど、
Honestly, it feels lacking. Honestly, it's lacking, but...
大好きじゃから、大好きじゃから歌わせていただきますのじゃ。
...since I love it so much, I'll let myself sing it.
うん。
Yeah.
そう、あるあるなのじゃ。好きなアーティストあるある。カラオケあるあるなのじゃ。
Yeah, it's a common thing. A common thing for artists you like, and at karaoke.
うん。
Yeah.
ま、でも、できる限り、できる限り頑張って歌わせていただきたいと、
Well, but, I want to do my best, my absolute best to sing it...
思いますのじゃ。
...for you.
うん。
Yeah.
じゃ、おぬしらに聴いてもらっちゃおうかな。聴いてもらっちゃおうかな。
So, shall I have you guys listen to it? Shall I have you listen?
よいしょ。
Yoisho.
それでは、聴いてください。よいしょ。
Now then, please listen. Yoisho.
トウキョウ... あっ、エコーつけるのありがとう、してくれて。
（トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ）
Tokyo... Oh, thank you for adding the echo effect for me.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ！ 毎回エコー忘れるのじゃ。
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous! I always forget the echo.
うん。
Yeah.
のじゃ！
Indeed!
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
Tuning up the radio waves, currently getting electrified!
のじゃ。
Indeed.
あなたにもわすれたいこと
I wonder if you have things...
悲しいこと あるのかしらね
...that you want to forget, or sad things too.
知らない映画なのに
Even though it's a movie I don't know,
涙を流すのは ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
...the reason I shed tears is because there's not enough drama.
そんな耳にも付かないこと
Things that don't even catch your ear,
くだらないこと 考えてばかりね
...I do nothing but think of such trivial things.
雨が上がれば愛もその夕暮れも
When the rain stops, both love and that dusk...
誰かのものになるのでしょう
...will probably belong to someone else.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部
Even this fake foundation is all...
今夜のためよ
...for tonight.
なのに一体全体如何して
But why on earth...
如何して何故何故ハテナー？
...how and why, what is the question?
不安定なカンテラ どこまで行くの
Unstable lantern, how far will we go?
あなた一切合切放り捨てて
You throw everything and anything away,
もう
...already...
冗談じゃないわ
This is no joke!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって如何にもならなげに
Even when the time comes, as if nothing can be done.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリーするだけ
Vague truths only make me feel melancholy.
あたしをさあ、攫って今テイクオンミー
Now, come on and sweep me away, take on me.
Yes!
のじゃ。
Indeed.
はーちゃんちゃらおかしいな法度ばっかりで食指がビクともしないわ
Ah, with nothing but ridiculous rules, my appetite isn't even stimulated.
実態の無い感情放っておいたって
Even if you leave these formless emotions alone,
策略なんてありゃせんのに何故？
...there's no scheme at all, so why?
あぁもう凝り凝りよ
Ah, I've had quite enough!
あなたのカットなる気質もじっと堪えて
Quietly enduring your hot-headed temperament,
取り繕ってはとうとう臨界点
...I kept up appearances until finally reaching my limit.
年がら年中リップサービス
Year-round lip service,
鈍感カマしては閉口
...acting dense and shutting you down.
どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは
Crashing and burning, the feel girl...
涙の目にも鬼
...is merciless even with tears in her eyes.
今や頭ん中のミュージックのせいで
Now, because of the music in my head,
あなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
...I can't hear a single word of your story.
少しは真っ当なこと言ってイエイエイエ
Say something decent for once, yeah, yeah, yeah.
回り出すターンテーブル
The spinning turntable...
全部全部忘れさせてよ
...make me forget everything, everything!
だけど一体全体如何して
But why on earth...
如何して何故何故ハテナー？
...how and why, what is the question?
不安定なカンテラ消えないままで
The unstable lantern remains unlit,
あなた一刀両断 食い違ってもう
...cutting you clean in two, even if we clash, already...
冗談じゃないわ
This is no joke!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって如何にもならなげに
Even when the time comes, as if nothing can be done.
不甲斐ないわ感情なんて
How pathetic, these emotions...
ランドリーで落とすだけ
...are just washed away in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック
Confirm things with me, Yellow Magic.
あいあいあ
Ay, ay, ay...
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって如何にもならなげに
Even when the time comes, as if nothing can be done.
冗談じゃないわ
This is no joke!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって如何にもならなげに
Even when the time comes, as if nothing can be done.
不甲斐ないわ感情なんて
How pathetic, these emotions...
ランドリーで落とすだけ
...are just washed away in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック
Confirm things with me, Yellow Magic.
あいあいあ
Ay, ay, ay...
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって如何にもならなげに
Even when the time comes, as if nothing can be done.
曖昧
Vague...
曖昧な本当なんて メランコリー化するだけ
Vague truths will only turn into melancholy.
あたしをさあ掻っ攫って 今テイクオンミー
Come on, snatch me away and take on me now!
Yes!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴでしたのじゃ！
That was Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, noja!
わー！
Yay!
緊張が解けた頃に歌って良かった
I'm glad I sang it once I started to relax!
どうじゃった？
How was it?
かっこよかったのじゃ？そうかの？
Was I cool? Was I?
うん、すごい好きな曲だからね いっぱい聴いてますのじゃ
Yeah, it's a song I really love, so I listen to it a lot, noja!
いっぱい聴いてますのじゃ！
I listen to it so much, noja!
え、なんかめっちゃ褒められちゃった
Oh, you guys are praising me so much!
めっちゃ褒められるのじゃ！
I'm getting so much praise, noja!
嬉しいのじゃ ありがとうなのじゃ
I'm so happy. Thank you, noja!
やったのじゃー！
We did it, noja!
そして、トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴを歌ったということは…
And since I just sang Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous...
残り、あと、1曲！
There is only... one... song left!
残りあと1曲になっちゃったのじゃー！
There's only one song left now, noja!
最後の曲ですのじゃ 次が
The next one is the last song, noja.
最後の曲ですのじゃ！
It's the final song, noja!
最後の曲は…
And the final song is...
やっぱホロライブの曲を せっかくじゃし歌いたいなって思ってて
Since we're here, I really wanted to sing a Hololive song, noja.
ホロライブの曲を歌いたいなって思ってて
I've been thinking about singing a Hololive song...
その前に、1個！
But before that, there's one thing!
1個だけお主に言いたいことがあるんだよ！言いたいことがあるんだよ！
Just one thing I want to tell you! There's something I want to say!
よいしょ、でか！でかいのじゃ
Here we go. It's huge! It's so big.
のじゃ のじゃ のじゃ のじゃ
Noja, noja, noja, noja...
言いたいことが1個だけあるのじゃー！
There's just one thing I want to say, noja!
あそびまわり隊！デビュー記念歌枠リレーが
The Asobimawari-tai Debut Celebration Karaoke Relay...
10月の8日、日曜日の20時から行われますのじゃ！
...will be held on Sunday, October 8th, starting at 20:00, noja!
歌配信するのじゃ あそびまわり隊で歌枠リレーをしますのじゃ！
We're doing a singing stream, a karaoke relay with Asobimawari-tai, noja!
だから、メラちゃんこれ今日絶対歌うと思ってたのに歌わなかったなーって曲あるじゃろ？
So, there must be songs you thought I'd definitely sing today but didn't, right?
正直メラちゃん絶対これ歌うだろって思った曲あるじゃろ？
Honestly, you probably thought "Mela will definitely sing this one," right?
今日聴けなかったけど「あれ歌うと思ってたんだけどなー」って曲が思い当たるお主ら！
For those of you thinking, "I didn't hear it today, but I thought she'd sing that one!"
あそびまわり隊デビュー記念歌枠リレーに来るのじゃ！
You've got to come to the Asobimawari-tai Debut Celebration Karaoke Relay, noja!
デビュー記念歌枠リレーで とっておいているのじゃ とっておいたのじゃ！
Yes, I saved those songs for our Debut Celebration Karaoke Relay, noja!
ので、またこれもね、Twitterの方で告知を出すので
So I'll be posting an announcement about this on Twitter too.
10月の8日の20時から空けておいてほしいのじゃ 4人で歌枠リレーをした後に
Please keep your schedule free from 20:00 on October 8th, noja! After the 4-person relay...
最後に4人でコラボで歌ったりしちゃおうかなって思っているので 楽しみにしていてほしいのじゃ！
...we're thinking of doing a 4-person collab song at the end, so look forward to it, noja!
うん、のじゃ
Yes, noja.
のじゃ
Noja.
もうすぐ1時間、良い時間になってきたのじゃ
It's almost been an hour. It's getting to be a good time, noja.
良い時間になってきたから ちょっとお水を入れてから最後の曲を歌うのじゃ
Since it's getting late, I'll pour some water and then sing the final song, noja.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ…
Here we go, here we go...
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ
There we go.
Pouring, pouring, pouring.
1枠どれくらい？ なんか20分くらいだった気がする
"How long is each slot?" I think it was about 20 minutes.
でもなんか、ちょっとちょっとずつだった気がする
But I feel like it was bit by bit, noja.
ごめん、なんか忘れちゃった 忘れちゃったのじゃ
Sorry, I forgot the details, noja.
飴舐めよう、飴舐めよう よいしょ、よいしょ
I'm gonna eat a lozenge. Let's have a lozenge.
飴舐めよう
Let me have a lozenge.
お主ら最後何歌うと思う？
What do you guys think the last song will be?
What do you think I'll sing last?
何が聴きたい？
What do you want to hear?
お主らホロライブの曲で わしが初めての歌枠で何聴きたい？
What Hololive song would you want to hear in my very first singing stream?
あ、SSSもわかるのじゃ 気持ちは分かりますのじゃ
Ah, I get why you'd say SSS, I totally understand!
うむ、わしがホロライブに…
Yes, when I joined Hololive...
入るきっかけになった
It was the catalyst...
曲が、ございますのじゃ。
...for joining, there is such a song.
わしがホロライブに
When I was entering Hololive...
「ホロライブ言えるかな」歌いだしたら超おもろいけどね
If I suddenly started singing "Can you say Hololive?", that'd be hilarious.
「ほらみんなで」って歌いだしたら超おもろいけどね
If I started singing "Come on, everyone...", that'd be so funny.
はい！
Yes!
ということで、最後の曲！
So, for the final song!
最後の曲は、Our Bright Parade
The final song is "Our Bright Parade".
歌わせていただこうと
I've decided to sing it...
歌わせていただこうと思いましたのじゃ
...yes, I decided to sing this one.
初配信でもお伝えした通り、わし
As I mentioned in my debut stream, I...
kemuさんが好きで、ボカロがすっごい好きで
...really like kemu-san and absolutely love Vocaloids.
ボカロPさんの提供曲を聞くのがすごい好きなんじゃが
I love listening to songs provided by Vocaloid producers.
その中でもkemuさんというボカロPさんがいらっしゃって、堀江晶太さんという方がおるんじゃが
Among them, there's a Vocaloid producer named kemu, also known as Shota Horie...
堀江晶太さんの提供曲を漁っていた時期があったのじゃ
There was a time when I was digging through Shota Horie's songs.
漁っていた時に、その曲の中に
And while I was digging through them...
Our Bright Paradeという曲があって
...there was this song called "Our Bright Parade".
見つけて、聴いた時に涙が出たのじゃ
When I found it and listened to it, I shed tears.
この曲に呼ばれたって思ったのじゃ
I felt like this song was calling out to me.
だから、わしにとってすごい思い入れがある曲を
So, a song that holds such special meaning to me...
初めての歌枠で歌わせていただこうと思って
...I wanted to perform it for my very first singing stream.
歌わせていただきたいと思いましたのじゃ
I really wanted to sing it for you all.
大切な曲なのじゃ。いい曲いっぱいあるんじゃけど
It's a very precious song. There are many great songs, but...
思い出補正みたいなのもあって
...there's a special emotional attachment to this one.
そう、いい曲いっぱいあるけど、中でも好きな曲なのじゃ
Yes, there are lots of great songs, but this is my absolute favorite.
ちょっと緊張するんじゃが、歌わせていただくのじゃ
I'm a bit nervous, but I'm going to sing it.
お主らは、お主らは高評価ボタンを押して応援してほしいのじゃ
I'd love for you guys, you guys to hit the like button and support me.
がんばりますのじゃ
I'll do my absolute best!
それでは、歌っちゃおうかな。よいしょ。
Well then, shall we sing? Here we go.
それでは、歌わせていただきますのじゃ！
Now then, please listen to my performance!
Our Bright Parade
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだ
We will shine!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal,
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにゆく
we go out to search.
スタートは何度だって
We can start over, anytime!
これが今日最後の曲ですのじゃ！
This is the last song for today!
ホロライブに入って一週間！
It's been a week since I joined Hololive!
これからも、がんばりますのじゃ！
I will continue to do my best from now on!
ただ 独り言を綴った
Simply penning a monologue,
ただ 始まりたくて走った
simply running, just wanting to begin.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit far away in the darkness,
それは 眩しすぎた名前
that was a name far too bright.
それは 優しすぎる思い出
Those were memories far too kind,
もっと 近づけと手を伸ばした
stretching out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず結び合った
Unexpectedly connecting with each other,
ほら今 迷子は僕等になった<
look, now the lost child has become "us".
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだ
Parade, Parade, Parade! We will shine!
悔しさも愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring along both the frustrations and the tenderness.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we can fly!
ささやかな祈りは光
Our humble prayers are light,
終わりなき兆し
an endless sign of what's to come.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of finding you.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here on out, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ頼りない予感を
Still clutching onto a fragile premonition...
Still a faint premonition...
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing, there's nothing to be ashamed of.
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary spell that nobody can break.
いつかまた会えるおまじない
A charm so we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that started from zero on that day.
数え切れない言の葉 数えるような想いじゃないさ
It's not a feeling where you can count the countless words.
ほら今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, right now, let's call us one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's beautiful.
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
A moment of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain, sun, kaleidoscope, a unique sky.
相応しい旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A fitting journey is to be with you...
君と在ることなんだ
...indeed, it is being with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば
If I hear "I'm home,"
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
I'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! We shine.
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ!
The ones who fill the darkness are you and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! We shine.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your frustration and your love along.
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A humble prayer is light, an endless sign.
君と 飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you, it's a wonderful start.
ここから これから
From here, from now on.
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
のじゃー
Noja!
うわあ
Whoa...
なんか感動しちゃうのじゃ、なんか感動しちゃうのじゃ。
I'm getting a bit emotional. I'm getting a bit emotional.
なんか、わしが、わし
Like, I... I...
画面の前にいたのに
...used to be in front of the screen.
わし、画面の前にいたのに
I was just in front of the screen.
もしかして、これから先、3Dになったりしたら
If I get a 3D model in the future,
おぬしらの前でリアルのライブとかで歌えちゃったりするんじゃろうか。
I wonder if I can sing in front of you all at a real live concert.
なんか
Somehow...
いつか
...someday...
いつかわしがステージに立っての、ステージに立っての、それでの、
Someday when I stand on the stage, stand on the stage, and then...
それをみたおぬしらの中から、かつてのわしみたいに、このライブに憧れる人が出ちゃったりするんじゃろうか。
I wonder if someone among you watching me might start to long for this stage, just like I once did.
まだまだめちゃくちゃほやほやの新参じゃけど、ね。
I'm still a super fresh rookie, but... right?
そういう、ね、わしに憧れる子がもしかして出ちゃうかも、出てきちゃうかもしれないのじゃ。
Someone like that, you know, might look up to me. Maybe someone like that will appear.
それってすごいことなのじゃ、
That would be amazing.
それってすごいことですのじゃ。
That would be really amazing.
それってすごいことなのじゃ。
へえ、すごいことなのじゃ。
Wow, that would be amazing.
まだわしデビューして一週間なのに。
Even though it's only been a week since my debut.
うーん、すごいことなのじゃ。
Yeah, that would be amazing.
ね。
Right?
不思議な話、運命みたいなのじゃ、なんか。
It's a mysterious thing, kind of like fate.
うん、のじゃ。
Yes, it is.
ね、わしが僕らになった。
You know, "I" became "us".
えー、すごいことなのじゃー。
Wow, that's amazing!
嬉しいのじゃ、すごい嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm happy. I'm so happy.
うん、今こうやって、ね、リアルタイムで、アーカイブでもきっと見てる人もたくさんいるじゃろうし。
Yes, right now like this, in real-time, and I'm sure there are many people watching the archive too.
いっぱいの人が見てくれて
So many people are watching,
わしのこととか、あそびまわり隊のことね、応援してくれて。
and supporting me and Asobimawaritai.
まだだってわしたち出会って一週間じゃよ。
I mean, we only met a week ago!
まだ一週間なのにさ、
It's only been a week,
it's only been a week,
わしたちのことをさ、応援してくれる人こんなにいっぱいいる。
and there are already so many people supporting us!
すっごいうれしいのじゃ。
I'm so incredibly happy!
こんなにいっぱいの人がわしたちのことを応援してくれてるのじゃ。
To think so many people are supporting us.
すごいありがたいことなのじゃ。
It's truly something to be grateful for.
ありがとうなのじゃ。
Thank you so much.
ね、こう一週間じゃの。
Yeah, it's only been a week.
でもこれから先もっともっとたくさんあるよ。
But there's so much more ahead of us.
もっともっとたくさん長い間、おぬしらと一緒にいるよ。
We'll be spending a very, very long time together.
うん。
Yeah.
応援してくれて嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm so happy you're supporting me.
これからも、これからもいっぱい応援してほしいのじゃ。
From now on, I want you to support me a lot too!
わしたちことこれからもいっぱい応援してほしいのじゃ。
Please continue to support us a lot in the future!
よろしくお願いしますのじゃ。
I'll be in your care!
うん。
Yeah.
「無理だけはしないで」
"Don't push yourself too hard."
うん、あのね、
Yeah, you know,
あの、無理しないように、あの、一週間に一回か二回ちゃんと休みも入れますのじゃ。
I'll make sure not to push myself and take one or two days off a week.
結構すでに心配してくれてる人がいる、わしのこと。
Some people are already worried about me.
うん。「大丈夫かな？」って心配してくれてる人いるし、
Yeah, they're wondering if I'm okay.
わしも慣れるまではね、ちゃんとお休みを取りつつも、長い間ね、
So until I get used to it, I'll take proper breaks so that, for a long time...
うん、長い間おぬしらと一緒にいたいと思ってるから、
Yeah, because I want to be with you all for a long time.
お休みをしつつ、配信をしつつ、
I'll stream while taking breaks,
おぬしらとずっと一緒にいれたらいいなって思いますのじゃ。
and I hope we can stay together forever.
うん。
Yeah.
ありがとうなのじゃ。
Thank you.
頑張るのじゃ。
I'll do my best.
うん。
Yeah.
ありがとうなのじゃ！
Thank you so much!
よいしょ。
There we go.
じゃあ...
Now then...
お知らせ！
Announcements!
お知らせ二度目！ドン！
Second announcement! Bam!
10月の8日日曜日20時から、歌枠をやりますのじゃ！
On Sunday, October 8th at 8 PM, we're having a singing stream!
あそびまわり隊デビュー記念歌枠リレーを行いますのじゃ！
We'll be doing an Asobimawaritai Debut Memorial Singing Relay!
あそびまわり隊の4人で、
The four members of Asobimawaritai...
歌をね、何十分かずつ歌って、
will each sing for tens of minutes...
最後に4人で歌う、歌枠リレーをやりますのじゃ！
and then we'll all sing together at the end!
うん、10月8日は20時から空けておいてほしいですのじゃ。お願いしますのじゃ！
So please keep October 8th free from 8 PM! I'm counting on you!
のじゃ。
Naoja.
あとね、明日はね、8番出口で遊ぶのじゃ。
And tomorrow, I'll be playing "Exit 8".
ホラゲ？ホラーゲームみたい。
A horror game? It seems like a horror game.
やったことないからどういうゲームか分からないけど、
I've never played it, so I don't know what kind of game it is,
異変を見つけるゲームみたいなのじゃ。
but it seems to be a game about finding anomalies.
うん。あ、一応言っとこう。
Yeah. Oh, let me just mention this.
配信の最初にも言ったんじゃけど、
I said this at the beginning of the stream too,
あの歌枠はJOYSOUNDさんのカラオケ音源を使わせていただいているので、
but since we are using JOYSOUND's karaoke audio for the singing stream,
歌唱部分、お歌を歌ってる部分の切り抜きは禁止なのじゃ。
clipping the singing portions is strictly prohibited.
歌ってるところは動画で切り抜かないで、
Please do not clip the parts where I'm singing.
もしなんか「拡散したいな」って思ったらURLをツイートするのじゃ。
If you want to share it, please tweet the URL.
URLをツイートして、「ここの何分何秒からの〇〇って曲がめっちゃ良かったんだよね」ってツイートしてほしいのじゃ。
Tweet the URL with "The song at MM:SS was amazing!" instead.
で、もしツイートしてる人を見かけたら、あのそっとしておいてほしいのじゃ。
And if you see someone doing that, please just ignore them.
うん、あのその辺のね、「駄目だよ」って言ってるのをやってる人へ注意するのはね、
Yeah, warning people who are doing things they shouldn't...
きっと会社の方がね、やってくださるので、
is something the management company will handle.
そういう人見つけても何も言わずに静観するのがインターネットリテラシーの高きもの。
Even if you find someone doing it, keeping quiet is a sign of high internet literacy.
うん、インターリテラシーの高いサラマンダーを、を見ているおぬしら、メラ組のおぬしらはそういう人を見ても、
Yes, you, the Mela-gumi members with high internet literacy...
しー、なのじゃ。
should just keep quiet.
うん。
Yeah.
そして、
And also,
お願いしますのじゃ！
please keep that in mind!
うん。
Yeah.
ホラーね、苦手。
I'm bad at horror games.
どれぐらい苦手かというとね、あの、トースターが怖いくらい苦手。
To give you an idea, I'm so easily scared that even toaster pops startle me.
うん。トースターが怖いくらい苦手。
Yeah, so scared that a toaster frightens me.
トースターでビビっちゃうくらい、びっくり系のホラーが苦手じゃから、
I jump at pop-up toasters, so I'm really bad at jumpscare horror.
ちょっとどうなるか分からないけど、
I don't know what's going to happen,
どうなるかなーって思ってるけど、
I'm a bit worried, but...
うん。
Yeah.
まあ、楽しみにしていてほしいのじゃ。
Well, please look forward to it.
頑張りますのじゃ。
I'll do my best.
今日の配信はこの辺でおしまいにしようかな。
I think I'll wrap up today's stream around here.
おしまいにしますのじゃ。
I'll be ending the stream now.
また明日！また明日会いたいのじゃ。また明日会いたいのじゃ。
See you tomorrow! I want to see you again tomorrow!
そして見てくれた人いっぱい、コメントもね、あの、
And to everyone who watched and commented...
アーカイブとか、歌枠じゃからアーカイブとか聴いて、「あ、この曲のここの部分の...」
since it's a singing stream, please listen to the archive and let me know which parts you liked...
あ、メラちゃん好きだな、みたいのがあったら、あの、コメント欄の感想ね、わし見てるからね
If you think "Oh, I like Mela," I read the feedback in the comments, you know!
あの、ここが好きなのじゃ、みたいな感じでね、あの、コメントで教えてくれると
So if you could let me know in the comments
嬉しいのじゃ
like "I love this part," I'd be so happy!
お願いしますのじゃ
Please do!
たくさん聞いてほしいのじゃ
I hope you listen to it a lot!
のじゃ！
Noja!
じゃ、最後の挨拶、さらばじゃでおしまいにしますのじゃ
Alright, let's wrap things up with our final greeting, "Saraba-ja"!
お主ら、いくぞ、いくぞ、いくぞ、いくぞー！
Everyone, here we go, here we go, here we go!
今日も配信見てくれてありがとうございましたのじゃ
Thank you so much for watching my stream today!
それでは、さらばじゃー！
And with that... Saraba-ja!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
[Thank you for watching!]